Inventory of the Valéry Giscard d'Estaing speeches and writings
Hoover Institution Archives
Valéry Giscard d'Estaing speeches and writings
1974-1981
80012
Hoover Institution Archives
4 manuscript boxes (1.6 linear feet)
Transcripts of speeches, election statements, and transcripts of press conferences and interviews, relating to the 1974 presidential election in France, and to subsequent French governmental domestic and foreign policy.
Giscard d'Estaing, Valéry, 1926-
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1980.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
President of France, 1974-1981.
Scope and Content of Collection
Transcripts of speeches, election statements, and transcripts of press conferences and interviews, relating to the 1974 presidential election in France, and to subsequent French governmental domestic and foreign policy.
Elections--France.; France--Foreign relations--1945-; France--Politics and government--1974-1981.; Statesmen--France.
- Extracts of speeches, April 22-May 17, 1980 (Box-folder 1: 1)
- Speeches, 1977-1981
  - July 1977-February 1981 (Box-folder 1: 2-3)
  - June 1980-February 1981 (Box-folder 3: 4-5)
- Press Conferences, March-June 1980 (Box-folder 1: 4)
- Interviews, 1974-1981
  - 1974-1981 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - May 1980-January 1981 (Box-folder 3: 3)
- Emissions, 1974-1980 (Box-folder 1: 6)
- Actualities Magazine, April 1974 (Box-folder 1: 7)
- 1974 Presidential Campaign, April 16-May 27, 1974
  - Summaries 1 -10 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Summaries 11-26 (Box-folder 2: 1-2)
- 1981 Presidential Campaign, March-May 1981
  - Summaries 1-6 (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - Summaries 7-39 (Box-folder 4: 1-3)
- Foreign Relations materials, 1980-1981
  - German Relations, July 1980 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Romanian Relations, July 1980 (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - Le Conseil Européen, December 1980, March 1981 (Box-folder 3: 6)